Did you know
My friend
Only 60 years old
She just stood for a while
She has back and leg pain
Only walked a few steps.
She is like this
panting
Shhhhhh
He couldn't sleep well at night
Is there any way
Can be solved
Yes
There is a kind of
Pāi bā xū (transliteration)
Do you know
Have you heard of it?
Pāi bā xū (transliteration)
No need to sweat
No need to buy any equipment
In just 10 minutes, the qi and blood will flow smoothly.
Sleep well
The whole person will feel relaxed
so good
Hurry up and say it.
We all want to try
Hu Naiwen start talking
I'm your old friend, Dr. Hu.
I want to share this episode with you
1. 8 places where Qi and blood are most likely to be blocked
Problems will arise if there is a blockage
2. Leg weakness due to long sitting
Pat it to reduce swelling and strengthen your legs
3.40 years old is busy and tired
Pat 2 places to help you sleep
4. People with three highs and obesity can tap here
to stabilize blood pressure and prevent stroke
5. It is best to Pāi bā xū (transliteration) at two times
4 types of people you shouldn't pat
8 places where Qi and blood are most likely to be blocked
Problems will arise if there is a blockage
Which master
invented the bā xū (transliteration)?
It couldn't have been invented byhuángdì(transliteration)
You are right
2000 years ago
The Yellow Emperor's Classic of Internal Medicine mentioned
The wordbā xū (transliteration)
What are the bā xū (transliteration)?
In traditional Chinese medicine, xū (transliteration)
The body structure is relatively empty.
There are sunken areas
That is where the Qi and blood
are weak.
The human body
There are 8 depressions
Two elbows, two armpits, two thighs, and two backs of the knees
These 8 are called the bā xū (transliteration)
These 8 places
What to do if it doesn't flow smoothly
The body will first
show some small warning signs
Like cold hands and feet
numbness
The joints will become stiff
Sometimes get cramps
Chest tightness
legs are swollen and weak
Some people think
It's just a minor symptom
It doesn't matter
It's a big deal
The bìng qì (transliteration) will get stuck there.
Always entangled there
Your internal organs will be hurt.
In the Yellow Emperor's Classic of Internal Medicine
There was a great man namedQí bó(transliteration)
He said when your bìng qì (transliteration)
Stuck at the elbow
It means there is something wrong with the lungs and heart.
What if the bìng qì (transliteration)is blocked in the armpit?
It may be liver
What will go wrong?
When bìng qì (transliteration)
Stuck at the base of both thighs
That is, theBì(transliteration)
That is the groin area
The spleen is already weak.
And itsYùn huà (transliteration)has also deteriorated.
when your bìng qì (transliteration)
Concentrated on both Back of the knee
It's behind the knee
It's the popliteal fossa
It means the kidneys are not good.
Leg weakness from sitting for a long time
Pat it to reduce swelling and strengthen your legs
You have swollen legs and back pain
Are you too tired to walk two steps?
Come and pat here
The area behind the knee is called the popliteal fossa
This is the tài yáng páng guāng jīng (transliteration)
Places passed by
The blood here
What if it gets stuck?
The whole leg will be blocked
It's blocked. It's stuck.
This action is particularly suitable for
Office workers
who have to sit for eight hours at work
The driver who never got out of the car
sit for two hours just to watch a TV series.
The mother-in-law who can't get up
You pat here now.
Eliminate immediatelyShī qì (transliteration)
Eliminate leg swelling
If you pat the right spot
The whole leg can be unobstructed
Now, going to pat Back of the knee.
The Back of the kneepit is
The soft area behind the knee
called popliteal
So how do you pat it?
Empty palm
Empty palm is on this knee
That is the soft flesh behind the knee
Just pat it lightly
It's that simple
The one with knee pain
Can pat?
Two situations
The first
You just have knee degeneration.
But not serious
No redness, swelling, heat or pain
You can gently pat the popliteal fossa
This is no problem
The second
You have acute pain
Swollen and broken skin
Don't pat yet.
40 years old is busy and tired
Pat two spots to relieve stress and sleep well
People who are under a lot of stress and have trouble sleeping
Just pat these two places
Armpits and elbows
Pat it while taking a bath
Pat of it during lunch break
Get rid of the pent-up qì
Qi and blood flow smoothly
People will feel relaxed.
Young people now
It's very hard
Go to work during the day
have to take care
of parents at night
And put the kids to sleep
Spinning like a top
can't sleep well at night
also feel chest tightness
Poor
good
Because the pressure can cause Qi to get stuck in your chest.
The armpit is the main intersection of theGān jīng (transliteration)
Did you know
The Qiis stuck in that place
People will feel depressed
can't sleep well when depressed
What are the benefits of patting your armpits?
It can relieve chest tightness
Help you relieve stress
Can also relax
Armpit pats
Just three pats
three more two more one more
You said three more
one more
Beautiful wife
Okay, come on, come on, do it again.
Take another pat
cubital fossa
How effective is it?
Enhance cardiopulmonary function
Enhance immunity
Keep you away from viruses
and the current epidemic
The invasion of COVID-19
A great point to remember
Elbow here
There are three jīng luò (transliteration) passing through
Fèi jīng xīn bāo jīng and xīn jīng(transliteration)
You often take a pat
These three jīn luò (transliteration) at once
All patted.
The same is true for the cubital fossa
pat this empty palm
Gently on the elbow
So gently pat
1 2 3 4 5
Don't pat too hard
Otherwise, there will be bruises.
This won't look good.
You have qì xū (transliteration)
And the problem of getting out of breath when walking?
Pat your elbows
Open up your heart and lungs
People will not be out of breath
Tired
Spend two minutes every day before bed
Pat your armpits and elbows
Armpits and elbows
Sleep well at night
feel better at work the next day.
Three highs obese people pat here
Stabilize blood pressure and prevent stroke
Come come come
Are you a mature person
with three highs problems?
The most feared thing is poor blood circulation
The legs often lack strength
The blood pressure fluctuates between high and low
So where should we pat?
pat
Liǎng bì(transliteration)
Right here in the groin
The blood in your body
Flow from the upper body to the legs
It will pass through the bì (transliteration)
If it's blocked here
Qi and blood cannot flow down
Stuck here
What kind of problems will there be?
Both feet tend to get cold easily.
No strength
Your heart will be overworked.
It's more laborious
Rush the blood downward
Blood pressure will become unstable
Come again
The bì (transliteration) fossa is here
It's the crotch area
This is also the case
Let’s take 5 pats.
1 2 3 4 5
It is best to Pāi bā xū (transliteration) at two times
4 types of people you shouldn’t pat
Beautiful wife
I'll teach you how to Pāi bā xū (transliteration)
Remember the gestures
The gesture is to pat with an empty palm
When Pāi bā xū (transliteration)
The gestures must be correct
That is, arch your palm.
It's like holding a bowl
Like this
Then this hand is a little bent
Then come pat
So am I right?
This is the right way
The second point
The direction of the pat
Remember to go from top to bottom and left to right
Pat gently
Come on, stand up too.
pat like me
pat the left side first and then the right side
pat with me
Pat while reciting this formula
Pat your elbows to warm them up
Pat your armpits to help you Qi more freely
Patting the thighs strengthens the liver qi
Pat your Back of the knee to make your legs feel lighter
After the pat
The skin should also be red
There's a little red dot.
Is this normal?
That's normal.
congratulations
Indicates yourjīng luò (transliteration)
It's starting to flow smoothly.
Don't some people doguā shā(transliteration)
It will be like this, right?
But
Be careful
Don't think you pat too many
The more the better
The better the metabolism
Just pat like crazy
got bruises from the pat.
That won't work
I have a patient
Just tell me about this
He pats this place
Whole bruise
I said what's going on?
Right?
Okay, did you hear that?
It's not okay to pat too much
Yes
That's great.
Can pregnant women Pāi bā xū (transliteration)?
No way
Pregnant women cannot pat
There are 4 types of people you shouldn’t pat
Pregnant women, those with skin wounds
A person who is currently menstruating
Children, please don't pat
These people are more sensitive
The pat is wrong
Something might happen.
What's a better time to pat?
There are two suitable time points
After you get up in the morning
Or 2 hours before going to bed at night
Just take a pat
Only then can the Qi and blood flow freely
Helps you sleep better
So, mothers
you can
Finished pat in the morning
Then go
Buying vegetables at the market
That's great.
Pāi bā xū (transliteration) helps you to circulate Qi and blood
More exercise for better results